Curriculum Vitae

Name: Jos Olminkhof

Profile: Senior Product Manager / Senior Sales Engineer

Born: 27 June 1963, Groenlo, Netherlands

Address: 21805 Esmalte, Mission Vieio, CA 92692, USA

Telephone: +1 949.355.5992 Email: jolminkhof@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/josolminkhof/

Summary of Qualifications

Successfully delivered on various complex assignments in technical sales, professional services, and product management in Europe and USA. Passionate about customer success. Speak fluent English, German, Dutch as well as some French. Expert in imaging, enterprise content management (ECM), business process management, security, analytics, and counter fraud. Possess industry domain expertise with significant contributions to solutions in the areas of financial services, healthcare, insurance, government, oil and gas.

Core competencies include:

Client Consulting | Leading and Integrating Multidisciplinary Teams | Public Speaking | Running Workshops | Providing Technical Training | Analyzing Complex Problems | Defining Requirements | Product Management

Professional Experience

Experian, Costa Mesa, CA, USA **Senior Product Manager Fraud & Identity**

Sept 2017 – Jan 2019

- Managed product roadmap, and increased revenue of my products 50%+, after 1 year of service.
- Enhanced the Fraud & ID portfolio by launching 2 new microservices SaaS products, and 2 combined Experian/partner offerings, adding support for new use cases.
- Wrote user stories, and as product owner guided international team of developers on scrum sessions.
- Presented roadmap and TOI for new products to internal teams.

IBM, Watson Health and ECM (FileNet acquisition), Costa Mesa and San Diego, CA, USA Offering Management Lead / Product manager / Solutions specialist

April 2005 - Sept 2017

- Successfully managed a variety of ECM and Imaging products. Applied IBM Design Thinking. Delivered value and increased customer satisfaction for existing and prospective ECM and Watson Health clients.
- Collaborated with customers and partners and internal teams, to define product strategy.
- Enabled closing of various sales opportunities by collaborating with a team of Senior Specialists. Added fraud investigation capabilities based on IBM Case Manager to 3 complex counter fraud solutions.
- Conducted live demos before clients and in web casts with 100+ attendees. Created videos, articles, whitepapers.
- Delivered presentations for large audiences at more than 10 conferences. Presented multi-day workshops.
- Mentored and trained a team of interns in design, development and delivery of complex high-impact demos and labs, using mobile and cloud technology, leading to 2 interns being hired as IBM employee.

FileNet, Boston, MA, USA

Senior Systems Consultant ECM

Dec 2003 - March 2005

- Developed complex FileNet P8 Proof of Concepts that helped win various customers for FileNet.
- Helped generating new sales by supporting several banking customers in New England area.
- Mentored colleagues on the job.

- Played crucial role in several large deals in banking and government.
- Integrated ECM with client infrastructure across Europe.
- Taught classes in administration and use of API's of FileNet ECM and BPM products, in Germany, France and the UK.

Adobe (through acquisition of Frame Technology / Curo Technology) Eindhoven Area, the Netherlands **European presales engineer**Aug 1994 – July 1996

- Contributed to customer success in pre-sales and professional services across Europe.
- Contributed new components to Curo's ECM software.
- Taught classes in administration of ECM software.

Education

- **MA Equivalent;** "Ingenieur" degree in Applied Physics from University of Twente in Enschede, the Netherlands, evaluated in the USA as a Master's degree.
- Data Communication and Telematics; 250 hour post-graduate study at Haagse Hogeschool in The Hague, the Netherlands.

Certifications / Certificates

- HIPAA
- IBM certificates: Cloud Computing; Cognitive Computing and Machine Learning; Text Analytics; Blockchain Essentials;
 Data Science for Business; Cloud Essentials; Big Data Foundation; Data Science Foundations; IBM Cloudant Indexes and Queries (Acclaim certificates are available on my <u>LinkedIn profile</u>)
- IBM Expert Level Certification: in Software, Client Support, Technical Training, Requirements Definition, Software Documentation and Product Management specializations
- FileNet Certified Professional: Administrator and Developer for Image Manager, Content Manager, Business Process Manager and Records Manager
- FileNet Certified Professional: Systems Consultant Technology Certification
- FileNet Certified Professional: Sales Certification

Training

Project Management; Agile Development; Product Design Methodology; Offering Management; Quality Management (healthcare); Enterprise Architecture (Zachman); Pragmatic Marketing; Product Management; Procurement; Intellectual Property; Information Security; Patents, Audits; Trademarks; MS Server Core Technologies (1 week), MS SQL Server Admin (2 weeks); Oracle Administration and Performance Tuning (2 weeks), Cloud Computing; Natural Language Processing; Cognitive Computing and Machine Learning; Deep Learning 101; Big Data 101; Data Science 101; Data Privacy; IBM Watson Conversation Service Foundation; Enterprise Architecture (Zachman); Service-Oriented Architecture; SAP portfolio and SAP ESA & NetWeaver; Making Effective Presentations; Video Editing.

Product knowledge

FileNet P8, IBM Case Manager, IBM Content Navigator, IBM DataCap, IBM Forms, Content Classification, ILOG / ODM (business rules), Blockchain, Master Data Management, Salesforce, Siebel, IBM Watson (cognitive analytics), SPSS (statistical and predictive analytics), i2 (link analysis), Softlayer (cloud), VMware & ESX (virtualization), Box (cloud), MS SharePoint, SAP, ILOG / ODM (business rules), Rational Team Concert, WebSphere, BEA Weblogic, MQ Series, Cognos, StoredIQ, IBM Watson Explorer, Verse, Lotus Notes, Bluemix, JIRA and Confluence, Eclipse (IDE), TechSmith Camtasia Studio, Mural.ly, Slack, Trello, MS Word, Excel, Powerpoint.

Program languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML, Java, JSON, ASP, C++, Visual Basic, SQL, Stored Procedures.

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, AIX, HP Unix, Apple iOS, Android.

Databases: MS SOL Server, Oracle (incl. performance tuning), DB2, MongoDB.

Other: Various API's, J2EE, SOA, HA/DR, DICOM, EMPI.